messenger.com 2003-06-18

# Avaya

**Privacy Statement  **

**Avaya Inc. and its worldwide affiliates (collectively "Avaya")** have long recognized that individuals with whom we conduct business value their privacy. However, in order to conduct global business in this increasingly electronic economy, the collection of personal data is often necessary and desirable. It is Avaya's goal to balance the benefits of e-business with the right of individuals to prevent the misuse of their personal data. 

**The Collection of Personal Data.**

In order to access and use of certain Avaya websites or parts of websites, Avaya will request personal data from you, like your name, e-mail address, company name and telephone number ("Personal Data). Avaya uses this information to customize your experience on our website and provide you with a password to use these websites, or for the purposes stated at the time of collection, such as participation in a promotion. By using these Avaya websites, and/or providing such responses, you will be deemed to have consented to the use, transfer, export and retention of your Personal Data as set out in this privacy statement. In addition, Avaya may use this information for other business purposes, such as alerting you to products and services that can assist you in your business, promoting site registration, and assisting in order processing. Avaya will maintain Personal Data in a secure environment. Avaya aims to ensure that any personal data it processes is accurate. **You may view and update or amend your personal data held by Avaya by changing your profile information on the site(s) for which you have registered or by contacting[AvayaWebTerms@avaya.com](mailto:AvayaWebTerms@avaya.com) .**

**Transfer of Personal Data.**

**WHEN YOU SUBMIT PERSONAL DATA TO AVAYA, YOU ACKNOWLEDGE AND AGREE THAT AVAYA MAY TRANSFER MY PERSONAL DATA TO, AND RETAIN AND PROCESS MY PERSONAL DATA IN, THE UNITED STATES, REGARDLESS OF THE COUNTRY IN WHICH YOU REGISTERED. IF YOU DO NOT APPROVE OF SUCH TRANSFER, PROCESSING AND/OR RETENTION, DO NOT SUBMIT PERSONAL DATA TO AVAYA.**

**Collecting Domain Information.**

Avaya also collects domain information as part of its analysis of the use of this site. This data enables us to become more familiar with which customers visit our site, how often they visit and what parts of the site they visit most often. Avaya uses this information to improve its web-based offerings. This information is collected automatically and requires no action on your part. 

**Disclosure to Third Parties.**

In cases where we believe your business interests will be served, Avaya may share your Personal Data (with the exception of account, credit card and ordering information) with Avaya BusinessPartners, who can alert you about new products and services to improve your competitive edge. 

Avaya may disclose aggregate statistics about our site visitors, customers and sales in order to describe our services to prospective partners, advertisers and other reputable third parties and for other lawful purposes, but these statistics will include no personally identifying information. Avaya may disclose personal data if required to do so by law or if it believes that such action is necessary to protect and defend the rights, property or personal safety of Avaya, the site or its visitors. Avaya may disclose your personal data in the event of any sale or transfer of its business or assets. 

**Use of Cookies.**

Some Avaya websites use "cookies," which are small files that the site places on your hard drive for identification purposes. These files are used for site registration and customization the next time you visit us. You should note that cookies cannot read data off of your hard drive. Your web browser may allow you to be notified when you are receiving a cookie, giving you the choice to accept it or not. By not accepting cookies, some pages may not fully function and you may not be able to access certain information on Avaya websites. 

**Your rights.**

**YOU MAY HAVE A LEGAL RIGHT TO A COPY OF ALL THE PERSONAL DATA ABOUT YOU HELD BY US. YOU ALSO HAVE A RIGHT TO CORRECT ANY ERRORS TO YOUR PERSONAL DATA.**

**Avaya reserves the right to change, modify or update this statement at any time without notice so you should check it each time you visit the web site for which you registered.**
